Kmerge Boimilleyr Dosdos

Software Engineer

© Cebu City, Philippines, 6000

+63 950 921 7939

in linkedin.com/in/kmergeboi

github.com/boboimilleyr

⇔ codepen.io/kmerge_boi

Summary

Detail-oriented developer with 1+ year experience in web development and a background in multiple programming languages. Passionate in building valuable software with good UX designs. Highly organized, self-motivated, and enthusiastic team player. Always eager to learn new technologies and transform more ideas into reality.

Experience

Sep 2021 - present

Freelance Web Developer

- Developed responsive websites for clients using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, PHP, WordPress and other technologies.
- ▶ Built custom WordPress themes.
- Turned mockups into usable web presence.

Jun 2021 - Jul 2021

Software Engineer Intern @ Alliance Software, Inc.

- Wrote programs in C# using .NET framework components like LINQ for data querying and Spire.XLS for excel files manipulation.
- Created interactive mockups designs using Moqups.
- Communicated and collaborated with project leads, technical and design reviewers, and fellow engineers on a daily basis.
- Recognized as one of the top 5 outstanding performers out of 20 interns.

May 2020 - Jun 2020

Associate Software Engineer @ Systems and Experts

- ▶ Automated sales invoicing process using Robotic Process Automation with
- Developed the company's RPA marketing website using WordPress and Elementor page builder.
- Worked closely with the marketing team to develop and manage the RPA marketing site.

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

Math and Physics Tutor @ Greater Heights Educational Solutions

- ▶ Tutored about 3 students per week in Math or Physics subjects.
- Provided students with helpful study habits and exam strategies.

Education

2018 - 2022

BS Computer Science @ University of the Philippines Cebu

Graduated Cum Laude

Skills

Languages

JavaScript, Python, PHP, C/C++, C#, SQL, HTML, CSS

Front end

React, Redux, Bootstrap, Kivy

Back end

Express.js, MongoDB, APIs

Tools

VS Code, Git, Node.js, WordPress, Notion/Trello, Chrome DevTools

Leadership

College of Science Representative

University of the Philippines Cebu University Student Council, 2019 - 2021

President

University of the Philippines Dormers Association, 2018 - 2019

Vice President

Madridejos National High School Supreme Student Government, 2016 - 2018

Layout Artist

The Northern Ripples Publication, 2016 - 2018

Languages

- English
- Filipino

Interests

Artificial Intelligence, Sports, Photography, Startups, Augmented Reality